<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="cottoninfo"> &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Cotton is one of the most important fibers and
        a cash crop of India and plays a dominant role
in the industrial and agricultural economy of the country. Cotton is the most important fiber
crop not only of India but of the entire world. It provides the basic raw material (cotton fiber) to
the cotton textile industry. Cotton in India provides a direct livelihood to 6 million farmers and
about 40-50 million people are employed in the cotton trade and its processing. Indian cotton
production is heavily associated with the intensive use of hazardous pesticides. Data reveals
that Cotton cultivation in India consumes <b>44.5%</b> of the total pesticides used in the country. In
addition, cotton is a water-thirsty crop and around <b>6%</b> of the water for irrigation in India is
used for cotton cultivation. Its seed (binola) is used in the vanaspati industry and can also be
        used as part of fodder for milch cattle to get better milk<br>\n</br><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
       <br><big><b>The factors for the growth of Cotton in India are:
        </b></big>\n</br>

        <br>1) Large favorable fertile Ganga Delta region.\n</br>
        <br>2) Plenty of chea labor.\n</br>
        <br>3) Introduction of insecticide to kill Boll Weevils\n</br>
        <br>4) HYV seeds like Sujata,Bharati\n</br>
        <br>\n</br><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>
        Cultivating cotton in rotation method is very important. Cotton should be followed by
        crops like <b>hybrid sorghum, Sugarcane, maize, banana etc </b>Cotton should not be followed by cotton
        as it increases pest and disease problems.\n</br>
        <br>\n</br><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>
        <b>Gujarat, Maharashtra, Punjab, Uttar Pradesh, Tamil Nadu, Andhra Pradesh are the
            principle cotton producing states in India</b>\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="typesofcotton">
        <br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <b>a) Long staple cotton:</b>
        <br>
        &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;It has the longest fiber whose length varies from <b>24 to 27 mm</b>. The fiber is long, fine and
shining. It is used for making fine and superior quality cloth. Obviously, it fetches the best
price. There has been rapid progress in the production of long-staple cotton since
Independence. About half of the total cotton produced in India is a long staple. It is largely
grown in <b>Punjab, Haryana, Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Madhya Pradesh, Gujarat, and Andhra
Pradesh.</b>\n</br><br>\n</br><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>
            <b>b) Medium staple cotton:</b>\n</br>
            <br>
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;The length of its fiber is between 20 mm and 24 mm. About 44 percent of the total cotton
production in India is of the medium staple. <b>Rajasthan, Punjab, Tamil Nadu, Madhya Pradesh,
Uttar Pradesh, Karnataka, and Maharashtra</b> are its main producers.\n</br><br>\n</br><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
<br>
    <b>c) Short staple cotton:</b>\n</br>
    <br>
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;This is inferior cotton with fiber less than <b>20 mm</b> long. It is used for manufacturing inferior
cloth and fetches less price. About 6 percent of the total production is of short staple cotton.<b>
U.P., Andhra Pradesh, Telangana, Rajasthan, Haryana, and Punjab</b> are its main producers.\n</br>


    </string>


    <string name="cottonrequire"> <big><b>The hot and moist climate is ideal for cotton farming. The climate condition  for cotton
        cultivation is mentioned below:</b></big>
           <br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;<b>70%</b> of cotton is rainfed. Clear sunshine and proper moisture level during boll
            formation is required. Moisture stress from <b>60 days to 120 days</b> directly reduces the yield.
More sunshine and warm humid climate favor the growth of the cotton crop. The low
            temperature at the boll opening creates a problem in the harvest.\n</br>
        <br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
<br><b>1.Temperature:</b> 250C is ideal for cotton cultivation.\n</br>
<br><b>2.Rainfall:</b> 150 cm to 200 cm rainfall is essential for cotton farming. Moisture in the wind is
necessary.\n</br>
<br><b>3.Soil:</b> Irrigated cotton should be grown on medium black to deep black soil having a <b>pH
    range between 6 to 8.</b> Saline soils are not suitable for cotton cultivation. Soil should have
    proper drainage. The depth of soil should <b>not be less than 20 to 25 cm.</b> It is advised to go for
a soil test before cultivating the cotton.\n</br>
        <br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br><big><b>Soil Preparation in Cotton Plantation:</b></big>\n</br>
        <br>
In Cotton production, the preparation of a good flatbed is very important. This can be done by
plowing and disc harrowing. Plowing should be followed by harrowing operation making the fine
til soil particle. For an advanced method of drip irrigation soil should be well prepared. Add 4
to 5 tons of well-decomposed FYM or compost before the last harrowing. In the soils having
termites or white grub, <b>add 750 to 1000 Kg/ha of Neem cake</b> along with FYM.\n</br>
    </string>

<string name="dis1">
    <b><big>Symptoms</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
    <br>Brown or gray spots on leaves surrounded by a red halo, elongated
        red-purple cankers on stems cause the wilting and death of leaves above\n</br>
</string>

    <string name="cure1">
        <b><big>Management</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>PNo fungicides are currently registered for use in cotton; plow crop debris into soil after harvest,
            crop rotation has little to no effect of control of disease.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="dis2">
        <b><big>Symptoms</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
    <br>Wilting of cotyledons and seedling leaves, cotyledons become chlorotic at the edges and then necrotic,
        older plants exhibit symptoms of wilting and leaf chlorosis; wilting is usually gradual but may be pronounced after heavy summer rain,
        if infection is severe plants become stunted and may be killed,
        vascular system of infected plants becomes discolored and can be seen by cutting the stem.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="cure2">
        <b><big>Management</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>Use on certified, disease-free seed, plant varieties with higher resistance to
            the disease in areas with a history of Fusarium diseases, fumigating the soil may reduce disease incidence.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="dis3">
        <b><big>Symptoms</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
    <br>The symptoms can be found on leaves, boll bracts and on bolls. Initially the appearance of small chocolate brown spots
        which later enlarge to become circular to irregular spot with target markings. The symptoms are mainly seen in the lower canopy.
        Typically the infected leaves retain their green color or green yellow color. Under severe conditions leaf and
        flower drop may occur.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="cure3">
        <b><big>Management</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>Use available resistant varieties. Follow crop rotation. Spray suitable fungicide.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="dis4">
        <b><big>Symptoms</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
    <br>Water-soaked spots on leaves which are delimited by leaf veins, giving them an angular appearance,
        lesions increase in size and turn black and necrotic; leaves drop from the plant,
        disease may also cause elongated gray-black lesions extending from the leaves to petioles and stem which are known as the
        "blackarm" phase,
        severe blackarm symptoms may cause the stem to be girdled,
        water-soaked lesions may be present on bolls,
        boll lesions enlarge and become sunken and brown-black in color.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="cure4">
        <b><big>Management</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>The use of resistant cotton varieties is the most effective method of controlling the disease,
            cultural practices such as plowing crop residue into soil after harvest can also limit disease emergence.\n</br>
    </string>


    <string name="dis5">
        <b><big>Symptoms</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
    <br>Small soft bodied insects on underside of leaves and/or stems of plant,
        usually green or yellow in color, but may be pink, brown, red or black depending on species and host plant,
        if aphid infestation is heavy it may cause leaves to yellow and/or distorted, necrotic spots on leaves and/or stunted shoots,
        aphids secrete a sticky, sugary substance called honeydew which encourages the growth of sooty mold on the plants.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="cure5">
        <b><big>Management</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>If aphid population is limited to just a few leaves or shoots then the infestation can be pruned out to provide control,
            check transplants for aphids before planting; use tolerant varieties if available,
            reflective mulches such as silver colored plastic can deter aphids from feeding on plants,
            sturdy plants can be sprayed with a strong jet of water to knock aphids from leaves,
            insecticides are generally only required to treat aphids if the infestation is very high -
            plants generally tolerate low and medium level infestation; insecticidal soaps or oils such as
            neem or canola oil are usually the best method of control,
            always check the labels of the products for specific usage guidelines prior to use.\n</br>
    </string>


    <string name="dis6">
        <b><big>Symptoms</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
    <br>Holes in bracts associated with bolls; heavy feeding by young larvae leads to skeletonized leaves,
        shallow, dry wounds on fruit,
        egg clusters of 50-150 eggs may be present on the leaves,
        egg clusters are covered in a whitish scale which gives the cluster a cottony or fuzzy appearance,
        young larvae are pale green to yellow in color while older larvae are generally darker green with a dark
        and light line running along the side of their body and a pink or yellow underside.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="cure6">
        <b><big>Management</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>Organic methods of controlling armyworms include biological control by natural enemies which parasitize
            the larvae and the application of Bacillus thuringiensis; there are chemicals available for commercial
            control but many that are available for the home garden do not provide adequate control of the larvae.\n</br>
    </string>



    <string name="dis7">
        <b><big>Symptoms</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
    <br>Holes chewed in bases of bolls and insect frass around holes;oung caterpillars are
        cream-white in color with a black head and black hairs; older larvae may be yellow-green
        to almost black in color with fine white lines along their body and black spots at the base of hairs,
        eggs are laid singly on both upper and lower leaf surfaces and
        are initially creamy white but develop a brown-red ring after 24 hours and darken prior to hatching.\n</br>
    </string>

    <string name="cure7">
        <b><big>Management</big></b><br>\n</br><br>\n</br>
        <br>Monitor plants for eggs and young larvae and also natural enemies that could be damaged by chemicals,
            Bacillus thuringiensis or Entrust SC may be applied to control insects on organically grown plants,
            appropriate chemical treatment may be required for control in commercial. plantations.\n</br>
    </string>





</resources>